KRIS RENALDI

South Plainfield, NJ | (732) 593-7798 | krenaldi@comcast.net

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/krenaldi | Portfolio: https://krenaldi.github.io/ | GitHub: https://github.com/krenaldi

SUMMARY

Dedicated Full Stack Developer with experience building Full-stack applications with functional UX/UI. Extensive customer service, technical training, and project management experience during my time at AT&T. Expertise in network troubleshooting & debugging code. I'm always going the extra mile according for my customers who've nominated me for company recognition for my outstanding service at AT&T. My mantra is "It's better to be pro-active than reactive" from working on large scale projects. I love to learn new things as shown by my career path from Web Developer to Network Admin to Technical Account Manager to Full Stack Instructor.

TECHNICAL SKILL PROFICIENCY

Expert: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, APIs, Git/GitHub, Linux, Bash/Powershell, Bootstrap, Node.js, NPM, Webpack, SQL (MySQL), SASS, jQuery, Postman, Express, Agile Scrum, MS Office, Google Suite, NoSQL (MongoDB), React, Redux, GraphQL, Apollo, Docker, Kubernetes

Intermediate: Angular, TypeScript, AWS, Heroku, Jest, Adobe Photoshop

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Digital Media & Political Science, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Development, Rutgers University	2019
Front-End Web Developer, Udacity	2015
Six-Sigma Green Belt	2009
Certified Cisco Network Administrator (CCNA)	2004

PROJECTS

Genucel E-Commerce Site | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/genucel

Live Demo https://ancient-retreat-32530.herokuapp.com/

- Full Stack Developer utilizing the following stack: MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Apollo, Jest
- Fully functional e-commerce site utilizing JSON Web Tokens for user authentication and Stripe API for handling payments.
- Used GraphQL to send specific data between client and server using Apollo web service.

Spotify App | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/spotify-app

Live Demo https://coffecakes-spotify-app.herokuapp.com/

- Full Stack Developer utilizing the following stack: React, Node.js, Express
- Using Spotify API to create this Spotify clone that utilizes OAuth 2 and Styled Components.

Common Ground | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/Common-Grounds |

Live Demo https://krenaldi.github.io/Common-Grounds

- Backend Developer utilizing the following stack: JavaScript, AJAX, Firebase Real-time Database
- Incorporated User Authentication for users to register and login by email and password or social media login and stores login information along with profile information into a Firebase Real-time Database.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASG Inc, Holmdel, NJ (Remote) **Full Stack .Net Developer**, June 2021 – Present

Responsible for the analysis, design, coding, testing, documentation, and support of new software applications and enhancements to existing applications. Provide technology solutions to allow business units to achieve their objectives and goals. Working alongside Front-End Developers in Agile environment to ensure that all elements of software are consistent and functioning for ASG users.

• Stack: React, Postgres, C#.Net, Azure DevOps

K. Renaldi - Resume Page 1 of 2

Rutgers Division of Continuing Studies, Somerset, NJ Full Stack Flex TA/Instructor, May 2019 – Present

Teaching in-person class on the MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node) including focus on the latest versions of JavaScript (including ES6), CSS, HTML, MySQL, and Git.

- Guided up to 20 30 students to develop projects and assisted them with problem-solving/troubleshooting issues
 on their projects. Worked 1:1 with students to understand key technological concepts in development which
 resulted in reduction of the class drop-out rate by 10-15%.
- Emphasized the management and versioning of the code using Git and GitHub. Demonstrated how to resolve any
 conflicts that occurred from merging code from different sources and coached them on best practices on how to
 prevent such conflicts.
- Completed cohorts exceeded career services post-graduation outcomes standards by 13.85%
- Created lesson summary documents for the Full Stack curriculum.

AT&T - Piscataway, NJ

December 1998 - May 2019

Technical Account Manager, Apr 2010 – May 2019

Subject matter expert on circuit ordering software and service. Led online training & onboarding meetings. Developed and updated training documentation. Subject Matter Expert for large scale projects for **McDonald's**, **Panera Bread** and **JC Penney**.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance by having my projects activated and billed before target of 90 days and was consistently a top 5 performer on the team.
- Reduced backlog of 600+ open orders by 80% by having my team follow up with clients as to whether they want service or to cancel.
- Traveled to provide in-person training and coaching at domestic and overseas offices.
- Managed and coached a team of anywhere between 6 to 21 people depending on the product I was supporting.
- Slashed end-to-end cycle time for service ordering by several days and reduced number of rejects and defects to almost zero with the overseas team.

Process Engineer, Sep 2008 - Apr 2010

Trained and coached new hire agents for MIS & BVOIP service and circuit ordering. Developed new hire training documentation and assisted with the onboarding process for new engineers. Worked closely with Software Engineering teams to test and develop new ordering software.

• Earned Six Sigma Green Belt and worked with Quality Management team on a Service Delivery Six Sigma Project to streamline the process for a BVOIP product which saved the company an estimated \$823K annually.

Provisioning Technical Engineer, May 2000 - Sep 2008

Assisted clients with their circuit ordering, network design, and architecture in order for their networks to communicate over the AT&T backbone from their datacenter and performed performance management review and troubleshooting to ensure communication was up and stable. Worked on projects for **Office Depot** and **Pepsi**.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance with an average of 98% (exceeding the target of 90-95%) and Cycle Time with an average of 28 days (shorter than the target of 30 days). As a result of my performance, my team exceeded the On-Time Performance target with a 96% average and Cycle Time of 29 days.
- Earned 7 Commitment to Excellence awards awarded by customers and sales account teams for providing outstanding customer service for several high-profile clients such as La-Z-Boy, Crown Castle, Office Depot, and Motel 6.
- Managed and completed up to 60 projects in a given month.

Web Developer/QA Tester, Dec 1998 - May 2000

Wrote and updated technical documentation for publication on AT&T's internal Content Management System where the provisioning and technical support teams have a single resource to pull information on how to perform certain tasks. Performed QA tests on new software for documentation and feedback to the developers. Provided training of new software applications to the team

- Re-designed the layout and architecture of the site for easier search capabilities for end users utilizing HTML/CSS/JavaScript.
- Set up and maintained UNIX Web Server for developing and testing web applications that employees used to make their job function easier.
- Conducted late night testing of new software applications to ensure software is running per specs and ensure smooth migration to the new system.

K. Renaldi - Resume Page 2 of 2